Guide to the Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data 1882-1974
Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data
- Series: W.F. Supply Dept., W.E. Hawthorne Data - 1905-1965, G.E. & NRC
  - Relationship between M.I.T. & G.E., 1920 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Engineering Education, June 1920 Vol. X, #10, p.462
  - General Electric (G.E.) on National Research Council (NRC), 1924 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - General Electric (G.E.) on National Research Council (NRC), 1925 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Series: Chase E. Snow
  - correspondence of C.E. Snow on Stolls influence on Hawthorne tests, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Chase E. Snow, April 7, 1961
  - Catalog of Charles E. Snow papers (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Tech. Engineering News, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    in Union List of Serials, p.2741
  - Comparisons of Snow's 1927 article and version in M&W (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Mass. Institute of Tech. Alumni Association (MIT Alumni Register), 1955 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Charles E. Snow's work compared with Relay Assembly Test Room (RATR) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - James E. Ives letter on Illumination (Box 6, Folder 15)
    2 pages
  - Correspondence with Ward Harrison [G.E.] (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Series: Men on CIL
  - Matthew Luckiesh - correspondence (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - "Workers - Work Horses or Human Beings", 1930 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Matthew Luckiesh Editorial in Transactions of the Illuminating Engineering Society (TIES), Jan. 1930, Vol. XXV #1 - on more light for work even though evidence (from Hawthorne) seems to show no need for this (this is all Wreges folder Heading)
  - Pamphlet, Contributions of Lighting Research Laboratory to the Science of Seeing, 1911-1948 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    signed, compliments of Matthew Luckiesh
  - Letter from Matthew Luckiesh, to Charles D. Wrege, on Hawthorne Illumination Tests, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    [July 5, 1952] (4 pages)
  - Forrest McDonald, correspondence with Charles D. Wrege, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    8/28/1957
  - Correspondence with Ethel Mollan on Hawthorne, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    See D.A. Moore file 7/1/64 (empty folder)
  - Johnson O'Connor and Hawthorne Tests, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Harrison factors compared to procedures followed at Hawthorne (Box 6, Folder 24)
    in The HIT and Relay Assembly Test Room (RATR) - notes
  - General Lighting Plus", 1929 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Matthew Luckiesh, Trans. of Illum. Eng. Soc. (March, 1929) Vol.24, No.3, pp.233-252 (empty folder)
- Series: Men in Illum. Tests, John Mudroch Correspondence
  - Notes for John Mudroch Tape, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    6/5/64 [on National Research Council (NRC) and Relay Assembly Test Room (RATR)]
- Series: Franke
  - Helen Oldham, M.I.T., letters on Franke, Parsons et al (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence on National Research Council (NRC) with Clarence E. Clewell, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence with William J. Donald on Hawthorne and the National Electric Light Association (NELA), 1957 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence with Henry E. Edmunds [Ford Motor Co.] on Ford & Hawthorne & Allen Nevins and John R. Lee's work at Ford (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Series: Correspondence with Samuel Hibben
  - Correspondence with Samuel Hibben, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Series: Maurice Holland Correspondence
  - Data on Frank B. Jewett and Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Series: Correspondence with Edwin Layton
  - Correspondence with Edwin Layton, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Series: Theodore K. Quinn Correspondence
  - Theodore K. Quinn Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - H.H. Wilson - Correspondence on Quinn & G.E., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    1 sheet
  - Correspondence and Gertrude Rand (of Feree & Rand), 1957 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    1 dated 9/7/57
- Series: Correspondence with John Scott
  - Clarence Stoll's statement on why Hawthorne Studies were started correspondence, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Data on Leonard Troland at Harvard correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Information on C.G. Stoll (Box 7, Folder 9)
    in: Personnel Research Federation Service Bulletin (empty folder)
  - The Industrial Lighting Situation - A Survey prepared for Professor Dugald C. Jackson by Henry Zeiger (Box 7, Folder 10)
    copy of manuscript
  - William Durgin photographs of Test Locations for Commonwealth Edison Company, Chicago, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    1.There are 7 photographs [#1 and #2 provided numbers by Charles D. Wrege] [#3,4,5,6, and 9, are original numbers]
  - William Durgin papers (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Hoover Presidential Library
  - Data on Dover Manufacturing Company, Dover, Ohio and correspondence, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Timken, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    also notes and article by Hess
  - Temperature, humidity and percentage of sunshine, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Columbus, Ohio - Jan - April 1923 Columbus, Ohio - use for Timkin Test. Data from U.S. Weather Bureau
  - Detroit Piston Ring Co. data - Detroit Piston Ring Light Tests. Correspondence, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence on Timken Roller Bearing Co. Illumination Test, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    2/15/1923 to 4/25/23
  - National Research Council - Industrial Illumination Research, 1923-1936 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Series: Thomas A. Edison and Hawthorne Studies
  - National Research Council (NRC) Material in Edison Lab, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    8/22/1957
  - Henry Zeiger - Survey on Industrial Lighting 1924 for National Research Council (NRC) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Office of Price Administration (OPA) Reports to Congress, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Mar-45
  - Service Trials on Ind. Illumination (E.W.) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Clarence Stoll Letter, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Sept. 3, 1957. Original handwritten letter
  - Data on Western Electric Supply Department, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Western Electric (W.E.) News July 1926, p.3
  - Western Electric Supply Department (survey of Advertisements in Light ), 1924-1928 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    September, 1924 to October, 1928
  - General Western Electric Files on Hawthorne etc (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "B" correspondence on Hawthorne Studies, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - L-M letters on Hawthorne, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Misc. Hawthorne Data, 1922-1941 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Owen B. ("Obie") Hunt (RATR designer). Personnel Record
  - Data on "Free - Lamp Renewals and the Hawthorne Studies", 1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    4 pages, offset, Western Electric Training Program (W.E.T.P.), 3-18-63
- Series: 1924-1925 Tests
  - "1924-25 Report on Hawthorne Illumination Tests", 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Charles E. Snow - original manuscript pages i-vi and pages 1-37
  - "1924-25 Report on Hawthorne Illumination Tests", 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Charles E. Snow - original manuscript pages 38-59
  - "1923-24 - Report on Illumination Tests", 1963 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Charles E. Snow - original manuscript pages 60-74, 77, 79, 80-83 [75-76, 78 missing] 8-29-63
  - 1924-25 Tests Report, 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Charles E. Snow pages 1-40 of Appendix
  - 1924-25 tests at Hawthorne, 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    Charles E. Snow pages 42-60 of Appendix
  - 1924-25 tests at Hawthorne, 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Charles E. Snow pages 61-66 of Appendix
  - Kata Thermometer Data (Box 8, Folder 21)
    10 pp
  - data on "Time Values Derived from Standards" - at Hawthorne, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Charles E. Snow 2 pgs
  - Chart and blueprint comparing Detroit Piston Ring, Ives Post Office, Harrison-Timken Roller Bearing, Hawthorne Tests, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Blueprint on Speed of Vision test for CIL of National Research Council (NRC), 1925 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    6/18/25 and data from p.96, Table III, Journal of Experimental Psychology (Jl. of Exper. Psych.) April, 1925
  - Bound - Historical Research Project, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    F.B. Jewett & Illumination Studies (Western Electric Co.) W.P. Cucco
- Series: Temperature - Humidity, 1924-25, Hawthorne, Snow "Log"
  - Original folder cover to Charles E. Snow's "Log Notes" from the 1924-1925 illumination tests at Hawthorne works of Western Electric (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Snow Log Notes", 1925 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Jan. 12, 1925 - Feb. 2, 1925
  - "Snow Log Notes", 1925 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Feb. 3, 1925 - Feb. 26, 1925 [first page of 2/21/1925 and 2/24/1925 missing]
  - "Snow Log Notes", 1925 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Feb. 27 - April 16, 1925
  - "Snow Log Notes" (Box 9, Folder 6)
    envelope 2 - no date
- Series: Geiss - Allphin
  - Allphin and Geiss (Box 9, Folder 7)
    pages 497-575
  - Correspondence with Wilard Allphin (Sylvania, Salem, Mass.), on Hawthorne and the National Research Council (NRC), 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Charles E. Snow data - Dept. 6325 - coil winding - receiver coils, 1924-1925 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Charles E. Snow data - Dept. 6329 - Relay Assembly - "E" type relays based on earnings and on direction of production, 1924-1925 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Charles E. Snow - Inspection Dept. - Jack Springs, Jack Shells showing direction of production, 1924-1925 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Charles E. Snow - Dept. 6325 Building 47-5, coil winding, Dept. 6329 Building 39-5 - relay assembly "hourly illumination averages" (by lighting period), 1924-1925 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Charles E. Snow - Dept.6325 Coil Winding Dept. - Induction coils (showing direction of production), 1924-1925 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Production results, 1924-1925 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Floor layouts of Hawthorne Buildings 37-4, 39-5, 47-5 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence with T. North Whitehead, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Re: Charles E. Snow Log Notes.
  - Correspondence with George E. Geis (of Allphin & Geis), 1958 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Geis & Allphin thesis an illumination, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    M.I.T. June 1, 1925 [for Drisko & National Research Council (NRC)]
- Series: 1925 Light Data
  - "A Year's Progress in Lighting", 1925 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    pages 701-707 on American Institute of Electrical Engineers (A.I.E.E.) Transactions, June, 1925
  - patent #1,536,844 for "Glassteel Diffuser", 1925 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Ward Harrison & John H. Waterbury - Official Gazette - U.S. Patent office Vol. 344, #1, May 5, 1925, p.238
  - Plan Book of Industrial Lighting Activity (Box 10, Folder 5)
    no date, but p.6 gives "schedule of Advertising Starting Aug. 1925 ending Jan. 1926"
  - P.B. Zimmerman, National Lamp Works (N.L.W.) on Industrial Lighting, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    in Light, October, 1925, p.16
  - "Daylight Recording at Edison Electric Illum. Company of Boston", 1925 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    H.J. Baker [use for Sunshine Data], Transactions of the Illuminating Engineering Society (T.I.E.S.) Vol. XX, No.5, May 1925, pp.512-522
  - Related events to 1924-1925 Hawthorne tests mentioned in issues of Hawthorne Microphone (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "Does Good Lighting pay its way in industrial plants?", 1925 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Ward Harrison, Factory, June 1925, pp.932-33
  - Advertisement for "Cooper - Hewett `Work Light'", 1924 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    from Factory, subtitled: "No more slowdown at sundown"
  - Advertisements of the Mississippi Wire Glass Company in Technical Engineering News, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Advertisement, "Sell Industrial Lighting Now", 1925 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Light Oct. 1925, p.2
  - Non-Mazda Lamps 1924-25 and 1925-26 Association of Edison Illuminating Companies (A.E.I.C.) Survey, 1924-1926 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "How to Save on Light Bills", 1926 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    System, the Magazine of Business (January 1926) Vol.XLIX, No.1, p.146 & 148
- Series: Whittemore
  - Letters with I.C. Whittemore, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Irving C. Whittemore's unpublished study on Illumination, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    for Jackson and National Research Council (NRC)
  - Progress reports, 1925-1926 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    no.3 1/1/25 (2 pg); no.4 3/1/25 (4 pg); National Research Council 4/1/26 (4 pg)
  - Charles E. Snow - Report of 2nd years test at Hawthorne, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    (original copy)[apparently not]
  - C.I.L. - "Progress Report" on 1926 Tests at Hawthorne (Box 10, Folder 19)
    Issued 2/17/26 by Dugald C. Jackson (on psychological test group) from National Research Council (NRC) Folder at Edison Archives
  - Charles E. Snow 1926 tests - Production & temperature (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - 1926 illumination tests at Hawthorne compared with 1924 tests, 1924-1926 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    includes charts and drawings of illumination tests H-51-57, H-61-68
  - Correspondence with Jules Daniels, [Boston Edison Company] on National Research Council (NRC) tests (Box 10, Folder 22)
    mentions Munsterberg on p.2
  - Drs. Ferree & Rand, "Intensity of Light and Speed of Vision, studied with special reference to Industrial Situations" part 1, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    Transactions of the Illuminating Engineering Society (T.I.E.S.), Jan.1927, pp.79-110
  - Percy W. Cobb and Frank K. Moss "Lighting & Contrast", 1927 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    Transactions of the Illuminating Engineering Society (TIES), Feb. 1927, Vol. XXII, #2 given Sept. 7-10, 1926
  - H. Higbie, "Control of Illumination from Windows", 1927 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    Transactions of the Illuminating Engineering Society (TIES), March 1927, Vol. XXII, #3 given Sept. 7-10, 1926, notes on
  - Data on Lighting, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    from Light Magazine
  - R.J. Lythgoe, "Illumination and Visual Capacities: A Review of the Literature", 1926 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    Med. Research Council, London (notes on)
  - Effect of Hawthorne Illumination Tests on Dr. Luckiesh, (also on honorary doctorate), including Light & Health data, also Luckiesh Miles Tinker Controversy, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - M. Luckiesh & A.J. Pacini on "Lighting & Production", 1926 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    Light & Health, p. 293, notes on
  - Charles E. Snow, outline of proposed final Report of National Research Council Studies, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Snow's 1927 article on Illumination tests (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Ralph G. Raymond, "Chicago Launches Another Offensive", 1927 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    Light, Jan. 1927, p.23
- Series: 1926-1927 tests
  - Charles E. Snow, 1926-1927 tests (Box 10, Folder 33)
    Ozalid of Retyped copy
  - Charles E. Snow's original, "1926-27 Tests", Report, 1926-1927 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    Ozalid copy 12 pages
  - Handwritten comparison of text & central groups at Hawthorne, 1926-1927 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Charles E. Snow "1926-1927 Tests" (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Handwritten data on: "Test Group Operatives", "Lighting Period Averages"
  - Charles E. Snow, later issued by C.I.L., "Progress Report", on 1926-1927 tests" (Box 11, Folder 3)
    October 7, 1926 - 2 pages
  - Charles E. Snow, "Report on 1926-1927 Tests" Progress Report on "Illumination Test - Dept.6325" test and control groups (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Dec. 30, 1926
  - Charles E. Snow, "sickness rates of test and control groups", 1926-1927 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Temperature and Humidity in 1926-1927 tests (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Photograph of Test Room in 1926-1927 Hawthorne illumination tests. Drawing of lighting arrangement in same room (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Charles E. Snow, Report on 1926-1927 tests. Table II a) "Test Group Operatives, Lighting Period Averages" b) "Control Group Operatives" (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Table IV 1926-1927 Tests [Charles E. Snow] (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Charles E. Snow - Drawing #L-15071, Illumination Test Demonstration Room", 1926-1927 tests, and chart #H-111 "Control Group #46 Induction Coils" (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Demonstration room became Relay Assembly Test Room
  - Charles E. Snow - Temperature & Humidity Record during 1926-1927 Tests (Box 11, Folder 11)
    [9/7/26 to 4/30/1927] (68 pages)
  - Progress Report of C.I.L., 1926 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Ozalid of Oct.28, 1926
  - Charles E. Snow "Progress Report" on "Illumination Test", "Test Group" - Dept.6325", 1927 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Jan. 19, 1927, copy
  - Charles E. Snow, "Progress Report", 1927 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Feb. 15, 1927
  - Charles E. Snow, "Progress Report" on "Illumination Test - Test Group Dept.6325", 1927 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Feb. 28, 1927
  - Charles E. Snow (comparison of product by test group and their machine speeds), 1927 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    14-Mar-27
  - Charles E. Snow - Compiliation of data on Dept.6643-5, 6329, & 6325 in "1924-1925 Tests", 1929 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    25-Mar-29
  - Complete set of tables summarizing illumination tests from 1924-1927 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Charles E. Snow, Handwritten copy of report on 6325, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - "Charles E. Snow 1926-1927 Tests" (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Program Report 1926-1927, tests (Box 11, Folder 21)
    Apr. 12, 1927
- Series: "Data on Special Illumination Test" (1927) or "Moonlight Test"
  - Special Illumination Test, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Feb., pg.1-20 copies 5/19/64
  - Special Illumination Test, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    Feb., 1927, p.2-20 copies 5/18/64
  - Special Illumination Test, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    Feb., 1927, p.3 20 copies 5/18/64
  - Special Illumination Test by Hebarger, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    Feb. 1927, p.4 5/18/64
  - Special Illumination Test by Hebarger, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    Feb. 1927, p.5 5/18/64
- Series: Sidebotham
  - Sidebotham photograph (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence with John Sidebotham Inc. (Phila. PA) on National Research Council (NRC) Tests (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence with John Sidebotham Tapp Mills on 1926 National Research Council (NRC) Tests (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - John Sidebotham Tapp Mills photographs, 2, 8"X10" photos number 22794 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Series: Dennison Test
  - Report Illumination Tests, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Dennison Manufacturing Company, Framingham, Mass. Sept. 19, 1925, Dugald C. Jackson, Chairman
  - Huse and Brainerd Illumination Tests in Philadelphia, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    E.W, p.1154 see also Sidebotham Tests
  - Correspondence with Arthur A. Brainerd on the National Research Council (NRC) and Hawthorne Tests (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Dennison Manufacturing Company [Framingham, Mass.] on National Research Council (NRC) Tests (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Report on Dennison Illumination Test (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Photocopy of Dennison Manufacturing Company test, 1924-1925 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    9/19/1925
  - Dennison Manufacturing Illumination Test, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    9/14/1925 (drawings)
- Series: Bridgeport
  - Correspondence with Jack Parsons on the National Research Council (NRC), 1964 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Charles E. Snow - Chart on Bridgeport Production (showing direction of production) tests, 1924-1925 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Series: Atkins Test
  - Earnest Atkins Illumination Test at Johns Hopkins, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Series: Whiting-Davis
  - Correspondence with Whiting & Davis Co. (Plainville, Mass.) on National Research Council (NRC) Tests (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Data on Whiting & Davis "Mesh Bag" Tests - National Research Council (NRC), 1926 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Charles E. Snow, teaching material on "Illumination 6.27" course at M.I.T., 1927-1928 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    given by Snow, Sept. - Jan. 1928
- Series: Snow Outline of Final Report on the National Research Council (NRC), 1928
  - Charles E. Snow "Suggested outline of Final Report, National Research Council, C.I.L." (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Photostatic copy of Snow's original "Authors reprint" of article in Tech. Engineering News, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Nov. 1927
  - Negative photo stats of "Suggested final Report National Research Council (NRC)" by Snow (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Charles E. Snow - First 2 pages of proposed final report on National Research Council (NRC) Tests, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    May-27
  - [Charles E. Snow] Negative photo stats of "Suggested Final Report, National Research Council (NRC)" (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Charles E. Snow, Photostatic copy of Snow's, "Suggested outline of Final Report", 1927 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    pgs.,2,3,4 and 5 1/16/64
  - Copy of actual published article by Snow in Tech. Engineering News, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Charles E. Snow article in Tech. Engineering News, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    Nov. 1927 (empty folder)
  - Dugald C. Jackson "Lighting in Industry", 1928 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    Bulletin of the Franklin Institute, March 1928
- Series: 1927-1930 Light Data
  - Industrial Lighting Tests, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - National Electric Light Association, Industrial Lighting Campaign, 1925-1926 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    from Charles D. Wrege, Phd. Dissertation, original Mss. pp.511-521
  - Ferree and Rand "Intensity of Light and Speed of Vision", 1929 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    Journal of Experimental Psychology Vol.XII, #5 (Oct. 1929) pp.363-391 notes on
  - Industrial Lighting Sales Campaigns by the National Electric Light Association (N.E.L.A.), 1925-1929 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    1 pg. note
  - Federal Trade Commission Data on Public Utilities, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Matthew Luchiesh, "Contributions to the Lighting Art from Researches in Light & Vision", 1928 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    Proc. Int'l Congress on Illumination, pp. 936-943
  - Matthew Luckiesh "General Lighting, plus", 1929 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    Transactions of the Illuminating Engineering Society (T.I.E.S.), Vol.XXIV, March 1929, notes on
  - Matthew Luckiesh on Hawthorne in Electrical World, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - G.E. Reaction to illumination tests at Hawthorne, 1927-1928 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - National Electric Light Association (N.E.L.A.) "Benefits of Industrial Lighting", 1928 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    N.E.L.A. Proceedings, Vol.85, p.575 table VI
  - Incandescent Lamp Bulletin, Public Service Company of Northern Illinois (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Incandescent Lamp Bulletin, Public Service Company of Northern Illinois, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Bulletin #21, Feb. 15, 1929 (Last issue)
  - [on "Light's Golden Jubilee"] Speeches by John W. Lieb, and the National Electric Light Association (N.E.L.A.); Elmer A. Sperry - on "Birth of an Industry", 1929 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Sperry 6/6/1929 (notes on)
  - Ward Harrison (on "Glassteel diffuser"), 1929 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    (see 1925 Light Data, page 18, item 4) ASME
  - Luckiesh, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Charles D. Wrege correspondence concerning: National Rural Electric Cooperatives Association (NRECA) Free Lamps Renewal Study 1) M.L. Cooke, 2) Ervin Baker, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Series: Lighting 1930-1965
  - U.S. Tariff Commission Report on Incandescent Electric Lamps Report #133, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - A. Zaccaria Jr. and M.E. Bitterman - Effect of Fluorescent Flicker on Visual Efficiency, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 36, #6, Dec. 1952 [original print]
  - Ernest J. McCormick, "Intensities of Illumination and a Motor Task", 1952 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 36, #3, June 1952
  - Data on Lamp Renewals by Public Utilities (Box 13, Folder 11)
    1922 & 1935 - compared
  - Correspondence with Russell School, Lurch Road, Cambridge 38, Mass, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    1/8/59 on report in Light Dec. 1936, Jan. 1937
  - "Effects of Adequate Lighting on Production" (Box 13, Folder 13)
    from "Light Conditioning - Industrys Power", Public Service Co., of Northern Illinois
  - "$600,000 waste exposed in Gas Works Operation", 1960 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    Phila. Inquirer, 3/8/60, p.39
  - "Code of Lighting: Factories, Mills and other work places.", 1930 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    from the Transactions of the Illuminating Engineering Society (T.I.E.S.) Vol. XXV, Sept. 1930, No.7
  - Correspondence with Theodore K. Quinn, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Letter from W.J. Pettyjohn, Jr. on "industrial lighting", 1959 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    9/2/1959